# SANTIAGO ARDILA

## Senior Backend Engineer

\$\ +573108768506 @ santidils7@gmail.com

#### **SUMMARY**

Systems and Computer Engineer from Universidad de los Andes with experience in architecture, design, and software development with highly complex data management. I have multiple certifications in Java, Node.js, and Agile development. I am passionate about learning new technologies, entrepreneurship, and the development of mobile computing and infrastructure solutions.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Senior Back-end Developer

01/2024 - 10/2024

#### Sonatafy Technology | Nearshore Software Development

Bogotá, Colombia

Software Development, Scottsdale, Arizona

- Implemented a new system based on the Spring framework to manage key data in an
  existing process.
- Established Domain-Driven Design (DDD) as the principal software development approach to address complex domain-related problems.
- Integrated the new system with legacy systems and connected it to various AWS services.
- Performed QA validations for both UI and backend features to ensure functionality and reliability.
- · Designed and optimized database schemas to improve data management.
- Developed and executed unit and integration tests to ensure code quality and system stability.

#### Software Engineer

05/2022 - 07/2023

Nubank

Bogotá, Colombia

Financial Services, São Paulo, SP

- Implemented new microservices using Kubernetes and Kafka to enhance system scalability and reliability.
- Refactored existing Clojure implementations to improve performance and maintainability.
- Developed and executed acceptance tests, along with integration and unit tests, for both new and existing features.
- Conducted data analysis to inform business and technical decision-making.

## Senior Java Software Engineer

10/2020 - 04/2022

# Modyo

Bogotá, Colombia

IT Services and IT Consulting, Vitacura, Santiago

- Connected digital sign service with the existing data system to streamline data integration.
- Maintained and optimized the existing microservices platform to ensure continuous operation.
- Led end-to-end development, ensuring successful deployment in the production environment.

# Java Software Engineer SSR Advance

03/2019 - 10/2020

Globant

Bogotá, Colombia

IT Services and IT Consulting, San Francisco, CA

- Designed and implemented RESTful APIs to enhance system functionality.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to ensure seamless integration of services.
- Optimized existing code for better performance and scalability.
- Developed and executed load tests to ensure system performance under high traffic conditions.



# **LANGUAGES**

Español Native ••••

Inglés Proficient ••••

# TRAINING / COURSES

IELTS Preparation (B2-Upper Intermediate)

## **SKILLS**

Java · Spring Boot · REST APIs · Scala ·

Relational Databases · PL/SQL ·

Load Testing · Docker · Microservices ·

DocuSign · Amazon Web Services (AWS) ·

API Development · Kubernetes ·

Google Cloud Platform (GCP) .

Spring Framework · Apache Kafka ·

Jenkins · Web Development ·

API Gateway · Serveless Development ·

 ${\sf Clojure} \cdot {\sf Git} \cdot {\sf Programming} \cdot {\sf Simulations} \cdot$ 

Software Engineering · Linux · Matlab ·

SQL · Process Optimization ·

Network design · C++ · C# ·

Software Development • Django • Python •

Flask · JUnit · IBM MQ · IntelliJ IDEA ·

Test-Driven Development •

Domain Driver Development

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Software Engineer

02/2018 - 02/2019

Seven4N

Bogotá, Colombia

IT Services and IT Consulting, Newtown, PA

- Implemented and optimized RESTful APIs to ensure seamless communication between microservices.
- Monitored and resolved production issues to maintain system stability.
- · Ensured compliance with security and regulatory requirements throughout the development process.
- · Developed and maintained Java-based microservices to support the ADVANCE project's functionality.

#### Graduate Research Assistant

08/2017 - 02/2018

## Universidad de los Andes - Colombia

Bogotá, Colombia

Higher Education, Bogotá, Colombia

- Responsible for the support of the creation of didactic material and contents in workshops for the Software Project Management course of the master's in software
- Maintenance of the Women in Computing website
- Development of the CIbSE website for the research forum 2018 Software Engineering (Software Engineering) leader in Latin America

#### **ABET Graduate Accreditation Assistant**

08/2016 - 02/2017

Universidad de los Andes

Bogotá, Colombia

Higher Education, Bogotá, Colombia

• Responsible for various activities related to accreditation granted by the international non-governmental organization ABET (Accreditation Board for Engineering and Technology) for the Systems and Computing Engineering program.

# **EDUCATION**

Master's in Software Engineering, Software Engineering Universidad de Los Andes	01/2016 - 12/2018 Bogotá, Colombia
Computer and systems engineer, Systems Engineering	01/2011 - 12/2016
Universidad de Los Andes	Bogotá, Colombia

